lavasoftsupport.com 2019-12-07

# Privacy Policy | Adaware: The best FREE Antivirus & ad block

**Adaware Privacy Policy**

Lavasoft Software Canada Inc. (Adaware) is a leading actor within the IT security field. We make every effort to protect the privacy of the users of the Adaware web sites, software, and mobile apps (we refer to these Adaware offerings throughout our policy as “Adaware Sites”). Among other things, in this privacy policy, we inform you of what type of personal information that we collect about you when you use the Adaware Sites. We describe the limited purposes for which we collect, process and share your personal information. And we provide information on your rights to the information that you provide us.

Please click on the link to the each section below to review more detail.  

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

**Customer Products and Support Details**

**User Account and Contact Information**

**Name and E-mail Address**

**Payment Information**

**Job Applicants**

**URLs of Flagged Websites**

**Data Trackers, Including** **Cookies** **and** **Web Beacons**

**Sensitive Personal Information**

**Information That Does No Longer Identifies You**

**Sharing Personal Information with Other Companies**

**Sharing Information for Business Purposes**

**Sharing Information In Case of Change in Ownership**

**Sharing Information to Meet Legal Requirements**

**Other Reasons We May Share Information**

**Links to Other Sites**

**Public Information**

**Information Collected By Third Party Web Search Providers**

**Security of Personal Information**

**How Long We Maintain Your Personal Information** __

**Transfers of Personal Information To Different Countries**

**Your Ability to Access and Control Your Data**

**Contact Information**

**Miscellaneous Provisions for U.S. Law**

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

Adaware may request that you provide certain personal information in order to use our services or engage in activities through the Adaware Sites. By "personal information" we mean any information that identifies you as an individual. This includes: your name, your postal address, your e-mail address, and some on-line identifiers. We collect this information carry out the services that you have asked from us and to help improve our products and services. We provide more detail below on what personal information we collect and why.  

  * **Customer Products and Support Details:**  
When you purchase any Adaware software products or services, we collect certain personal information about you and the products that you have purchased, including: 
    * Your name
    * Your e-mail address, and
    * Your product License number
We will use this information to send you user information about the specific Adaware software products and services that you hold a license for, including: 
    * Notices when the license is about to expire and
    * Software update information.

If you contact us for product support, we will maintain account notes on your product license number, hardware and the type of problems that you are experiencing. This helps us to track issues that you are experiencing and to further enhance our support for you.

Please note that certain support services offered through the Adaware Sites are not provided by Adaware, but by Adaware recommended support service providers. These support service providers can only collect and process your personal information to carry out the services we have asked them to do. They are required to meet both legal and industry standards to ensure that your data is protected. For more information about our service providers and partners with whom we share information, please see our section below on Sharing Personal Information With Other Companies.

  * **Name and E-mail Address:**  
If you have subscribed to Adaware newsletters, press releases and/or special offers, or if you enroll in the Adaware referral program, Adaware will ask you to provide: 
    * Your name
    * Your e-mail address

For the referral program, the information we maintain will be used for tracking and communicating back to you the completion status of your referrals.  

  * **Payment Information:**  
If you submit an on-line order for any Adaware software products or services through an Adaware online store, you will be asked to provide certain personal information to complete the purchase. This includes: 
    * Your name
    * Your Postal Address
    * Your e-mail, and
    * Your credit card details
Please note that the Adaware on-line stores are operated by a third party e-commerce service provider, [upclick.com](https://www.upclick.com/). Upclick.com’s privacy policy will apply for any personal information that you provide through the Adaware online stores. They also may maintain personal information that you provide them in connection with the purchase of Adaware software products and/or services. We encourage you to review the upclick.com privacy policy, which can be found here: [ https://www.upclick.com/privacy.html ](https://www.upclick.com/privacy.html).

  * **Job Applicants:**  
When you apply for a job with Adaware, we will ask you to provide us some basic information, including your name, email address and phone number. Additional information that you provide us is voluntary. We will not ask you and we will not collect from you sensitive information such as about your religion, health, sexual orientation, or political affiliation. And the information that you provide us will be used to communicate with you, manage our hiring process, and to comply with laws and regulations. If you are later hired, the information may be used for employment and corporate management purposes.  
 
  * **URLs of Flagged Websites:**  
Adaware maintains a list of urls that we have flagged as potentially suspicious. We do this to help support our products and protect our users.  
 
  * **Data Trackers, Including Cookies and Web Beacons** : "Cookies" are minor text files that are placed in your computer's browser and store your preferences. 
    * **Adaware Cookies:** Adaware uses cookies to understand how the Adaware Sites are being used and to improve the Adaware Sites content and offerings.  
Cookies do not provide Adaware with any personal information, however, if you provide Adaware with personal information through the Adaware Sites or elsewhere, that information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.  
Adaware may use cookies to personalize your experience at the Adaware Sites (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our site or to remember, at your request, your user name and/or password for certain user accounts). Adaware may further use cookies to create personalized offers for products and/or services.  
You may refuse Adaware's use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note however, that if you refuse cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all activities at the Adaware Sites and/or otherwise use the full functionality of the Adaware Sites.  
 
    * **Third Party Cookies:** Adaware uses Google Analytics, a web analytic service provided by Google, Inc. that uses cookies to analyze how our users use the Adaware Sites. The information generated by these cookies about your use of the website (including your IP _IP Address:_ “An Internet Protocol address (IP address) is a numerical label assigned to each device connected to a computer network that uses the Internet Protocol for communication.”  address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States according to Google’s privacy policy, which is subject to revision. Google may also transfer this information to third parties when required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. For more information about Google's privacy policy click [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

  * **Sensitive Personal Information:**  
Adaware does not collect any sensitive personal information through the Adaware Sites. We do not collect your social security number, credit card number or other personally identifiable financial information. However please note that some of Adaware's service providers and partners, such as our e-commerce partners, may collect such personal information in connection with activities that are initiated by you through the Adaware Sites. Those providers and partners are legally restricted as to how they may use your personal information obtained through Adaware. Adaware limits what personal information we collect and process through the Adaware Sites and we will not share this information with any third party except for the purposes specified by this privacy policy. For more information about our service providers and partners with whom we share information, please see our section below on Sharing Personal Information With Other Companies.

  * **Information That Does No Longer Identifies You:**  
Through some of the Adaware Sites and products, we collect certain data in order to improve our Sites and offerings, including for research and analysis and to protect our users. We make sure, however, that the data we collect keeps you anonymous and cannot be used to identify you. Some examples are: 
    * **Statistical Information.**  Adaware may share with third parties aggregate statistical information, i.e. information that does not identify you as an individual, but refers to certain Adaware users as a whole or as a group. Examples of such aggregate statistical information include the number of users that downloaded a specific product or number of users that clicked on a particular advertisement.  
 
    * For some of the Adaware products, we collect other information that does not identify you. Mentioned below in detail  
 
      * **Adaware Secure Search.** If you use Adaware Secure Search, a Chrome extension, we collect certain data at installation to help improve the product and your experience. This includes, geolocation, campaign tags, date and preferred search engine.  
 
      * **Adaware Web Companion.** When you install Adaware Web Companion, we ask if you would like to share some data that helps us to improve detection for potentially unwanted programs and otherwise improve our products and protect our users. It includes, the display name and version, publisher, install location and source.  
 
      * **Adaware ad block.** When you install and when you use Adaware ad block, we will collect the following information: install date; browser family, version, language and locale; ad block version and locale; IP address; update date; uninstall date; and feature state. We may also collect other data if certain features are enabled or if you agree to share data. But again, this data does not trace back to you.  
 
      * **Adaware H2O.** When you install Adaware H2O, we collect and aggregate (meaning it combines with other people’s general data and it cannot identify you) certain data about the installation including: what program you are installing, the code of the country where you are located, the session ID, OS version, and installed anti-virus applications.  
 
      * **Adaware Download Companion.** When you install and when you use Adaware download companion, we will collect certain data to help improve the product and your experience. This includes, product version, install data, update date, uninstall date, host browser family and version, OS version and bits, install source, and total downloads.  

**Sharing Personal Information with Other Companies**

  * **Sharing Information for Business Purposes:**  
From time to time, Adaware needs to share some of your personal information with companies that help us to run our business. The information we provide them is limited. We share with them only what they need to perform the services they carry out for us. And they are required by agreement to keep any and all personal information we provide them strictly confidential. These service providers have no rights whatsoever to use any personal information we provide them in any way other than for the purpose for which send it to them. Accordingly, these service providers are not allowed to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes or to share with any other third parties. Further, the Adaware service providers are required to meet both legal and industry standards to ensure that your data is protected.  
These other companies include: 
    * Hosting service providers that help us run the Adaware Sites;
    * Customer support service providers that help us handle your support requests; and
    * Marketing services providers that help us with our e-mail marketing campaigns, newsletters, press releases and/or special offers.  

  * **Sharing Information in Case of Change in Ownership:** Adaware may need to share your information should there be a change in our company ownership. 
    * In the event that we sell Adaware, Ltd. or the Adaware Sites, we may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
    * If Adaware or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, your personal data held by Adaware will be one transferred. This includes a merger, acquisition, sale, bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors’ rights generally, or other change of control.

  * **Sharing Information to Meet Legal Requirements:**  
Adaware may be required by law to disclose or share your personal information. For instance, 
    * In order to comply with any legal obligation or legal request, such as a subpoena;
    * To investigate and respond to third-party claims or allegations; or
    * In order to enforce or apply Adaware’s terms of use or terms and conditions and other agreements.

  * **Other Reasons We May Share Information:**  
 
    * **For fraud detection and prevention.** Adaware may need to disclose or share your personal information to protect the rights, property, or safety of the Adaware Sites, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.  
 
    * **Statistical information.** Adaware may share with third parties aggregate statistical information. But this information does not identify you as an individual. It refers to certain Adaware users combined. Examples of such aggregate statistical information include the number of users that downloaded a specific product or number of users that clicked on a particular advertisement.  
 
    * **With your consent.** We also may share information in other situations with your consent.  

  * **Links to Other Sites:** On the Adaware Sites you will find various links to the web sites of certain Adaware partners as well as offers for such partners' products and services that direct you to such partners' web sites. Adaware is not responsible for the content, business practices or operations of such web sites. Please note that these partners have their own privacy policies. If you link to our partners' websites from any of the Adaware Sites, we encourage you to read their partners' privacy policies before you submit any personal information on their sites. The presence of a link to Adaware partners' websites does not constitute or imply Adaware's endorsement, recommendation, or sponsorship of the content, goods, or services available through, or contained on, such partners' websites.  
 
  * **Public Information:** Please note that any and all information, discussions, opinions, blogs, postings, ideas, feedback and other communications and materials of any kind that you post, upload, submit or otherwise make available within the various forums, centers and communities on the Adaware Sites or elsewhere on the Adaware Sites will be considered public information and will not in any way be treated as confidential information.  
 
  * **Information Collected By Third Party Web Search Providers:**  
The web search services offered on the Adaware web sites are provided by other companies: Codefuel and Microsoft. For information on their data collection, please visit their privacy statements.  
The Codefuel privacy policy can be found at: [ https://www.codefuel.com/legal/end_user_privacy_policy](https://www.codefuel.com/legal/end_user_privacy_policy/).  
The Microsoft Bing privacy policy can be found at: [ http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=521839 ](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=521839) Both companies may _update their policies_ from time to time. If we change web search providers, we will update this privacy policy to include information on the new company.

**Security of Personal Information**

We take appropriate technical, physical, administrative and managerial procedures, and employ security measures and safeguards to protect personal information that is stored on our servers.

Where Adaware has given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Adaware Sites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. If you believe your password or account has been compromised, you should [notify Adaware ](mailto:dpo@adaware.com) immediately.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use commercially reasonable and appropriate technical, physical, administrative and managerial procedures, security measures and safeguards to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.  

**How Long We Maintain Your Personal Information**

Adaware will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with the product and services you have requested and as needed to comply with our legal obligations and enforce our agreements.  

**Transfers of Personal Information To Different Countries**

We primarily store information about our visitors, members, and customers in the Canada. However, we may transfer your personal information across national borders to other countries in compliance with applicable laws. For instance, as discussed under Third Party Cookies,” our analytics provider stores data in the United States. If you are a European resident, we transfer your data based European Commission-based Standard Contractual Clauses.

**Your Ability to Access and Control Your Data**  

In order to keep your personal information accurate, Adaware depends on you to amend your user account(s) to include updated contact details. You may update your user account by accessing it electronically through the Adaware Sites.

You have certain rights to access and control your data under the law of some countries. This includes the right to:

If you wish to learn more about what personal information Adaware maintains and/or to which third parties such personal Information has been provided, please contact us. Adaware will make reasonable efforts to respond to your request within one (1) month.

If you are an E.U. resident and you have a dispute about how we are handling your personal information, you have the right to complain to a supervisory authority to enforce your rights. You can contact Adaware’s lead supervisory at: [dpo@adaware.com](mailto:dpo@adaware.com).

Please note that if you request that Adaware delete personal information relating to you, you may no longer be able to continue to pursue certain activities at the Adaware Sites and/or to otherwise use the full functionality of the Adaware Sites.

  * Access the personal information that you provide us and that we maintain;
  * Restrict processing while we review any concerns you may have over the accuracy of the personal information we maintain;
  * Object to 
    * Data processing based upon legitimate interests,
    * Data processing for research or statistics,
    * Direct marketing, and
    * Decisions based exclusively on automated processing, such as profiling, so long as the decision does not impact our ability to enter or perform our contract services for you or is not based on your explicit consent;
  * Withdraw your consent in instances where we must have your consent to contact you; and
  * Transfer, or port, your personal information that you provided us in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format.

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please [contact us](mailto:dpo@adaware.com) at:

7075 Place Robert Joncas,  
Ville Saint-Laurent,  
Montreal, Quebec H4M 2Z5,  
Canada  
(+1) 514-448-1122  

You may also contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@adaware.com](mailto:dpo@adaware.com)  

**Miscellaneous Provisions for U.S. Law**  

  * **California Privacy Rights**  
We do not provide Your Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes. However, if You are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits You to request, once a calendar year, information regarding the disclosure of Your Personal Information by Adaware to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If applicable, this information would include the categories of Personal Information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2015 will receive information regarding 2014 sharing activities). To make such a request, [please write us](mailto:dpo@adaware.com).  
 
  * **Children's Privacy**  
Adaware further recognize the particular importance of protecting the privacy of children and Adaware is committed to protecting children's privacy on the Internet. Adaware does not generally target children and does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If Adaware would discover that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided Personal Information through the Adaware Sites or if Adaware is contacted by a verifiable parent or legal guardian about his or her child's participation on the Adaware Sites, Adaware will delete the Personal Information about the child from Adaware's active user records.  

**Amendments of this Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy will be updated by Adaware on a regular basis. We therefore recommend that you check the privacy policy periodically for modifications. Adaware will indicate when the privacy policy has been updated by noting the "Last updated" date at the bottom of this page.

Last updated: July 2018
